@article{Muhammed2023,
   abstract = {In today's scenario of rapid population increase and the unvarying land mass available, multi-storeyed buildings have become inevitable. The structures are more vulnerable to earthquake loads and wind loads as the height of the building increases which will produce lateral displacements and thus accumulates deformations in various members of the building i.e., beams, columns, etc resulting in storey drift. These parameter values may exceed the permissible limits or can even lead to failure of the building. Seismic Retrofitting is the modification of an existing structure to make it more resistant to damages caused to the building due to various earthquake loads. India is divided into four seismic zones i.e., zones II, III, IV and V based on historical seismic activity by the Bureau of Indian Standards among which zone III and IV are considered. Steel Bracings are one of the efficient ways to help the building be seismic resistant. A G+12 storey building is to be analysed using E TABS 2019 software for seismic zones III and IV. The building is analysed against the seismic loads for models that are unbraced, with X bracing, V bracing, Inverted V bracing, K bracing and diagonal bracing at middle and corner configurations. The main parameters to be compared are lateral displacement, storey drift and base shear and the most suitable bracing at both middle and corner configuration among them for both zones III and IV are identified.},
   author = {Ameena A Muhammed and Ifthana M N and Minnu Kurian and Shilpa Sajil and Merin Mathew},
   issn = {2395-0072},
   journal = {International Research Journal of Engineering and Technology},
   keywords = {ETabs software,Earthquake,Multi-storey Building,Seismic Analysis,Steel Bracing},
   title = {SEISMIC ANALYSIS AND RETROFITTING USING STEEL BRACING IN A MULTI-STOREYED BUILDING},
   url = {www.irjet.net},
   year = {2023},
}
@misc{Nasser2018,
   abstract = {The indiscriminate disposal of animal waste in the environment has led to the search for solution by recycling these wastes, which includes the use of animal bone waste in the construction industry, as a partial replacement of cement in concrete. The aim of this project is to study the properties of the concrete by partial replacement of cement with animal bone powder. The bone powder is replacing cement partially by weight in mix proportion (3%, 6%, 9%, 12% and 15%). The objectives of this research are to protect the environment from the harmful effects of animal wastes by using animal bone powder in concrete as a partial replacement for cement, to study the possibility of using animal bone powder in the concrete mix and to investigate the effect of animal bone powder on the compressive and the spilt tensile strength of the concrete mixture. Conduct preliminary tests on the basic materials, including fine aggregate, coarse aggregate and cement. The mix design was developed for C30 grade concrete using the ACI method. The mix proportion used is 1: 1.67: 2.34 with water cement ratio of 0.5. Cube samples with dimension of 150mm×150mmx150mm and cylinder samples of 150mm diameter and 300mm height respectively were used to prepare concrete mix. Concrete samples were cast during this study replacing the cement with the animal bone powder. A total of 18 cubes and 18 cylinders were cast in this study and the samples were cured in the water tank for 28 days under normal conditions. Cube samples were tested for compressive strength and cylinder samples for split test in a UTM. The research has shown that the use of animal bone powder as a partial replacement of cement in concrete can affect the properties of the concrete. The results of the experiments showed an increase in compressive strength and split tensile strength when compared with the results of the normal mix however; as the bone powder content increased a reduction in the workability of the concrete was observed and recorded. Furthermore, the results showed the optimal replacement percentage of BP in concrete is 6 percent with compressive strength of 36.2 N/mm 2 when compared with other replacement ratios. Therefore, from an environmental and technical perspective, there is an opportunity to utilize waste animal bones in concrete for construction applications.},
   author = {Nadia Nasser and Rashid Al-Bahri and Cornelius Kanmalai Wiliams and Eman Muhye and Adeen Muhye and Adeen Al-Hatali},
   keywords = {Animal bones,Compressive strength,Concrete,Partial replacement,Slump test,Split tensile strength},
   title = {Saudi Journal of Civil Engineering A Feasibility Study on the Mechanical Properties of Concrete by Replacing Cement with Animal Bone Powder},
   url = {http://saudijournals.com/},
   year = {2018},
}
@article{Murari2022,
   abstract = {The growing interest of using higher strength reinforcing steel for certain applications within the reinforced concrete industry is driven primarily by relief of congestion; particularly in buildings assigned a high seismic design category. Construction efficiency can be improved by high strength bar or combined with high strength concrete which allows reinforced concrete to be used in more demanding applications. High grade steel generally increases the cost as well allows smaller concrete member which creates a problem of placement of reinforcement. Therefore there is a need to study the better option between lower quantity of high grade and high quantity of lower grade. This paper presents the parametric study to see the effect of beam span and member sizes on the results obtained in design of simply supported flexural members using different rebar grades, such as Fe415, Fe500, Fe550 and Fe600 in terms of crack width and member deflections for mild and moderate exposure conditions. It was observed that detailing plays vital role in cost saving and crack width limit governs final steel requirement in moderate exposure condition. Cost analysis was also performed for different grades and Fe500 is found optimum grade.},
   author = {Krishna Murari and Harvinder Singh and Inderpreet Kaur and Savleen Takkar},
   doi = {10.38208/acp.v1.514},
   issn = {2830-909X},
   issue = {1},
   journal = {ASPS Conference Proceedings},
   month = {12},
   pages = {307-314},
   publisher = {Alwaha Scientific Publishing Services SARL},
   title = {Parametric Study to Decide the Optimal Rebar Grade for Flexural Members},
   volume = {1},
   year = {2022},
}
@article{Saje2013,
   author = {Drago Saje and Branko Bandelj and Jakob Šušteršič and Jože Lopatič and Franc Saje},
   doi = {10.1520/JTE20120134},
   issn = {00903973},
   issue = {6},
   journal = {Journal of Testing and Evaluation},
   month = {11},
   pages = {20120134},
   title = {Shrinkage and Creep of Steel Fiber Reinforced Normal Strength Concrete},
   volume = {41},
   year = {2013},
}
